Here we have an array called favoriteFlavors
这是一个叫做 favoriteFlavors 的数组
with ice cream flavors that I think are pretty awesome.
其中包含了各种美味的冰激凌口味
We got cookie dough, salted caramel, and toffee.
有曲奇饼 咸焦糖和太妃糖口味
Let's go ahead and use the forEach loop and loop through
我们使用 forEach 循环
every single flavor in this array.
循环访问该数组中的每种口味
So first, I'm going to call forEach on favoriteFlavors.
首先 我将对 favoriteFlavors 调用 forEach
ForEach takes in a callback as an argument.
ForEach 接收回调参数
So what you want to do at this point is pass in forEach,
现在 你需要传入 forEach
a function that's going to be called on every single flavor in that array.
系统会针对该数组中的每种口味调用该函数
Great. So what forEach is going to do is iterate through this entire favoriteFlavors
forEach 将循环访问整个 favoriteFlavors 数组
array and call this function on every single flavor in that array.
并对该数组中的每种口味调用该函数
So for the first one you should see I enjoy cookie dough, ice cream.
对于第一个口味 你应该会看到消息“I enjoy cookie dough ice cream”
Then let's move on to the next element, salted caramel.
然后是下个口味 咸焦糖
And you should see I enjoy salted caramel,
你应该会看到消息“I enjoy salted caramel ice cream”
ice cream, and also do the same thing for toffee as well.
太妃糖口味也一样
So let's see it in action. Cool. And that's exactly what happened.
我们看看运行效果 很酷 这就是发生的情况
It moves through cookie dough first and then forms a sentence.
代码首先访问曲奇饼口味 然后组成一个句子
And then it moves on to the next element in this array,
接着访问该数组中的下个元素
the next flavor in this array, salted caramel,
即下个口味 咸焦糖
and forms this sentence.
并组成这个句子
And then when it hits toffee,
遇到太妃糖口味时
it does the same for that as well.
执行相同的操作
So all that happened pretty fast.
一切发生得很快
What we can do is just put debuggier right there and see everything step by step.
我们可以在这里放置调试程序 逐步看看代码运行情况
Kind of see how far each iterates through the entire
可以看看每次迭代是如何访问整个 flavorFlavors 数组的
flavorFlavors array and forms every message one by one.
然后逐个组成句子
So first, what I want to do is reload so I get a little bit more space,
首先 我将重新加载下 以便有更多的空间
then I'm going to add debugger into the function that we pass into forEach.
然后向传入 forEach 的函数中添加调试程序
So now that we have the debugger in there,
现在这里有了调试程序
let's run this function step by step and see what's going on.
我们逐步运行该函数 看看发生的情况
So you can see right now we're in the function.
可以看到 我们现在位于该函数中
We're on this line debugger and
位于这个调试程序行
the current flavor that we're going through is cookie dough,
目前访问的口味是曲奇饼口味
which should be the first element in the array that we have over here. So great.
应该是数组中的第一个元素 在这里
We're starting at the very beginning. Let's go ahead
我们从最前面开始
and step through this one by one and see what happens.
我们逐步执行代码 看看发生的情况
So right now we're on the second line in this function on
我们现在位于该函数的第二行
the console log portion and the flavor is still cookie dough.
并位于 console.log 部分 口味依然是曲奇饼
Let's step through one more time.
再循环访问一次
And right now we're over here and I enjoy cookie dough,
现在位于这里 控制台中出现了
ice cream printed to the console.
“I enjoy cookie dough ice cream”消息
Great. Let's move onto the next one.
现在转到下一步
If we press it again,
如果再次按下这个按钮
we're now on salted caramel which is actually the second element in this array.
现在转到了咸焦糖 即数组中的第二个元素
So it looks like it's iterating through this favoriteFlavors array in order.
看起来是按顺序循环访问这个 favoriteFlavors 数组
Check on the next step. No surprises.
看看下一步 不出所料
We're still on salted caramel.
依然是咸焦糖
And this line has yet to be run [inaudible] You can see that this message,
这行依然尚未运行 我们运行它
I enjoy salted caramel ice cream is printed to the screen.
可以看到控制台中出现了“I enjoy salted caramel ice cream”这条消息
Let's move on to the final one. Now we're like on the last element in this array,
继续最后一步 现在是数组中的最后一个元素
the last flavor, which is toffee.
最后一个口味 即太妃糖
And if we play it again,
再次播放的话
we're on this line and once that line executes,
转到了这一行 该行执行时
we see I enjoyed toffee ice cream printed out to the console.
我们看到控制台中显示了“I enjoyed toffee ice cream”
Cool. Let's run all the way through.
我们从头运行整个代码
So there we have it. Let's recap what we did here.
结果是这样 我们总结下刚刚执行的步骤
We called the forEach,
我们对 favoriteFlavors 数组调用了 forEach
on the favoriteFlavors array which if I scroll up a little bit,
我向上滚动下
it's just an array of different strings cookie dough,
它是一个具有以下不同字符串的数组
salted caramel, and toffee.
cookie dough salted caramel 和 toffee
And what we did for every single element in this array was execute this function once.
我们对该数组中的每个元素都执行了一次这个函数